

# **Jorge Montecinos**

#### Career Summary

He is a professional dedicated to the develop and implementing solutions focused on data value. He's specialized in data science to get knowledge from data, applying descriptive and prescriptive analytics algorithms, also hi has skills in data engineering to build solutions bases for data science. With both skill sets he can cover cross-cutting ways for data analytic.

He has 25 years working with data and 5 years as Data Scientist, in many types of companies to provide technical solutions focused on data driven business goals.

# Summary of Qualifications

Proficient In:

Machine LearningNeural

Networks

Data
Analytics

Big DataCloud comp.

Python

• Spark

Databricks

# Languages

• Spanish (native speaker)

• English (Intermediate)

### Career History

### Perficient, Santiago, Chile

Apr. 2022 – to date

Data Scientist and Business Intelligent

• Data Analytics, reports and cubes from Loyalty and Awards system for MasterCard USA.

#### Axity, Santiago, Chile

Nov. 2021 – Mar. 2022

Data Scientist

• Design and implement Chilean Treasure Government forecast and budget data analytics with machine learning models, design of Data Lake, Synapse in Azure cloud platform.

# **Factor IT Engineer, Chile**

Jun. 2021 – Nov. 2021

Data Scientist

 Design and implement machine learning models for prescriptive and descriptive analytics for Shopstar (Peru) with e-commerce customer analytics and Brilla (Colombia) with loan risk classification. Develop custom models for Clustering, XGBoost classification (gradient boosting), Auto ML, Spark ML, in Google cloud plt. and IBM Whatson Studio in cloud plt.

#### **Synergistics Digital Solutions, Chile**

Oct. 2020 - Jun. 2021

Data Scientist

 Design and implement machine learning models and data platform to industrial control in copper mining for Anglo American Minerals. Develop classification model, clustering, data lake and Synpase analytics in Azure cloud plt.

#### Education

Universidad de Santiago de Chile, Santiago, Chile	Mar. 1991 – Dec. 1992
Bachelor of Computer Science	
Professional Institute CEC, Santiago, Chile	Mar. 1993 – Dec. 1995
Higher technician in analysis and programming	
Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT xPro remote), MA, USA)	Nov. 2020 - Jan. 2021
Data Science and Big Data	
Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT Pro educ), MA, USA)	Sep. 2019 - Nov. 2019

Machine Learning